Guide to the Stacy H. Geiken Photographs of Green Library, Bing Wing
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stacy H. Geiken photographs of Green Library, Bing Wing
1999
PC0090
Geiken, Stacy H.
0.5 Linear feet
These photographs were commissioned by the Stanford University Libraries to document the reopening of the Bing Wing of Green Library, which had been closed since the Loma Prieta earthquake of 1989. Selected images were used in the Fall 1999 issue of IMPRINT, published by the Associates of the Stanford University Libraries. Included in the collection are 35mm color slides, color negatives (35mm and 4x5 inch), black and white negatives (35mm and 4x5 inch), contact prints for both color and b/w negatives, and 4x5 color transparencies.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
Reproductions must be arranged through Stacy H. Geiken Photography.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Stacy Geiken is a San Francisco Bay Area professional photographer, specializing in corporate photography. He earned his B.A. in journalism at Stanford University and his M.A. in photography at the University of Michigan. He is co-founder and co-director of The Palo Alto Photographic Workshops. He has taught at the Brooks Institute of Photography, Lansing Community College, West Valley College, and San Jose City College.
Description of the Collection
These photographs were commissioned by the Stanford University Libraries to document the reopening of the Bing Wing of Green Library, which had been closed since the Loma Prieta earthquake of 1989. Selected images were used in the Fall 1999 issue of IMPRINT, published by the Associates of the Stanford University Libraries. Included in the collection are 35mm color slides, color negatives (35mm and 4x5 inch), black and white negatives (35mm and 4x5 inch), contact prints for both color and b/w negatives, and 4x5 color transparencies.
Access Terms
Geiken, Stacy H.; Stanford University. Libraries.; Photonegatives; Photoprints.; Slides.
Collection Contents
- Photographs
  - Color slides (35mm)
    - Desk carrels, 90.001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Desk carrels, 90.002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Desk carrels, 90.003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bender Room lamps, 90.004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bender Room lamps, 90.005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bender Room carpet, 90.006 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bender Room carpet, 90.007 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bender Room carpet, 90.008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bender Room carpet, 90.009 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rotunda pillar, 90.01 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rotunda light fixtures, 90.011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rotunda light fixtures, 90.012 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rotunda, with table, 90.013 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rotunda, with table, 90.014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rotunda, with table, 90.015 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rotunda air grille, 90.016 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rotunda pillar, 90.017 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Office doors off rotunda, 90.018 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rotunda dome, 90.019 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Rotunda dome, 90.02 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Special Collections reading room, 90.021 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Special Collections reading room, 90.022 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Special Collections reading room (grandfather clock), 90.023 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Special Collections reading room (floor detail), 90.024 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Special Collections reading room (desk lamp), 90.025 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Special Collections reading room (desk lamp), 90.026 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Special Collections reading room (desk lamp), 90.027 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - SSRC reading room, 90.028 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - SSRC reading room, 90.029 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - SSRC reading room, 90.03 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - SSRC reading room, 90.031 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - SSRC reading room, 90.032 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - SSRC reading room, 90.033 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - SSRC reading room, 90.034 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - SSRC reading room, 90.035 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - SSRC information desk, 90.036 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bender Room seating, 90.037 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bender Room seating, 90.038 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bender Room seating, 90.039 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - View of Quad from Bender Room, 90.04 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - View of Quad from Bender Room, 90.041 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View of Quad from Bender Room, 90.042 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View from Bender Room, 90.043 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View through Bender Room leaded glass windows, 90.044 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View through Bender Room leaded glass windows, 90.045 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View through Bender Room leaded glass windows, 90.046 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View through Bender Room leaded glass windows, 90.047 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - SSRC information desk, 90.048 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - SSRC information desk, 90.049 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Computer hookup in table, 90.05 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Computer hookup in table, 90.051 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Peterson Gallery, 90.052 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Peterson Gallery, 90.053 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View of exterior arcade, 90.054 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View of exterior arcade, 90.055 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View of exterior arcade, 90.056 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View of front entrance, 90.057 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View of front entrance, 90.058 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View of front entrance, 90.059 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Desk carrels, 90.06 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View from SPC door through rotunda, 90.061 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View from SPC door through rotunda, 90.062 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View from SPC door through rotunda, 90.063 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View of window wall of director's offices, 90.064 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View of window wall of director's offices, 90.065 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - View of window wall of director's offices, 90.066 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Rotunda dome, 90.067 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Rotunda skylight, 90.068 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Rotunda skylight, 90.069 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lane Room clock, 90.07 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lane Room, 90.071 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lane Room, 90.072 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lane Room wall shelves, 90.073 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lane Room wall shelves, 90.074 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lane Room wall shelves, 90.075 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lane Room wall shelves, 90.076 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Special Collections reading room, 90.077 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Special Collections reading room, 90.078 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Special Collections reading room, 90.079 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Special Collections reading room, 90.08 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Prints and negatives
    - Color negatives (35mm) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Color contact prints (35mm and 4x5) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - B/W negatives (35mm) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - B/W contact prints (35mm and 4x5) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Color negatives (4x5")
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda (marked # 1) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda (marked # 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda (marked # 3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda (marked # 4) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda (marked # 5) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda (marked # 6) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Director's Office looking out to portal (marked # 7) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Director's Office looking out to portal (marked # 8) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Front view, oblique (marked # 6) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Front view, oblique (marked # 5) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Front view, no fountain (marked # 4) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Front view, with fountain (marked # 3) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - View toward Quad (marked # 2) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - View toward Quad (marked # 1) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Exhibit gallery (marked # 5) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Exhibit gallery (marked # 6) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bender Room (marked # 8) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Bender Room(marked # 7) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Field Room (Special Collections reading room) (marked # 3) (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Field Room (Special Collections reading room) (marked # 2) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Field Room (Special Collections reading room) (marked # 1) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Field Room (Special Collections reading room) (marked # 4) (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - B& negatives (4x5")
    - Exterior, oblique view (marked # 1) (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Front view, no fountain (marked # 2) (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Exterior, oblique view (marked # 3) (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Front view, with fountain (marked # 4) (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - View from entrance to Quad (marked # 1) (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - View from entrance to Quad (marked # 2) (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Bender Room (marked # 1) (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Bender Room (marked # 2) (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - View from Director's office to portal (marked # 3) (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - View from Director's office to portal (marked # 4) (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Exhibit gallery (marked # 5) (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Special Collections Field Room (marked # 6) (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Exhibit gallery (marked # 7) (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Special Collections Field Room (marked # 8) (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda (marked # 9) (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda (marked # 10) (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda (marked # 11) (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda (marked # 12) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Color transparencies (4x5")
    - Exhibit gallery [Imprint, Fall 1999, p. 8] (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Bender Room [Imprint, Fall 1999, p. 79] (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - View from Director's office to portal (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - View from Field Room door through rotunda [Imprint, Fall 1999, p. 77] (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - View of Quad from front entrance [Imprint, Fall 1999, p. 73] (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - View of Quad from front entrance (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Front view, oblique (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Front view, oblique (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Special Collections Field Room [Imprint, Fall 1999, p. 75] (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Front view, no fountain (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Front view, with fountain (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - View down front arcade (Box 2, Folder 52)